A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Projects FA733
Rockefeller Archive Center
- C-319: University of Arkansas - Support research re: cooperative approach to campus-community television programming, 1957 (Reel P-1009)
- C-320: Support for the Central Personnel Service for the Social Science & Area Studies, 1957 (Reel P-1009)
- C-322: Institute of International Education - Clearing house on community organization for international visitors, 1957-1958 (Reel P-1009)
- C-324: University of Louisville - Funds for computing equipment for speed scientific school, 1957 (Reel P-1009)
- C-327: Worcester Youth Guidance Center - Support research on evaluation of community mental health education, 1957 (Reel P-1009)
- C-328: California Institute of Technology - Support for building to house nuclear equipment, 1957 (Reel P-1009)
- C-331: Economic Research Institute, American University of Beirut - Support for near east economic data book, 1957 (Reel P-1009)
- C-333: Citizens Educational Committee on Legislative Problems - Support for Wyoming conference on legislative problems, 1957-1959 (Reel P-1009)
- C-334: Cornell University - Support for fellowship program in political behavior (Reel P-1009)
- C-336: Yale University - Support for exploration of development activities in Latin America, 1957-1959 (Reel P-1009)
- C-341: Oxford University - Support for law library, 1957 (Reel P-1009)
- C-342: Syracuse University Research Institute - Support for study in development of authoritarian personality, 1957 (Reel P-1009)
- C-343: Mannerheim League for Child Welfare - Support for establishment of family & child study center in Finland, 1957 (Reel P-1009)
- C-344: University of Manchester - Support for study in social research, 1957 (Reel P-1009)
- C-346: University of Pennsylvania - Support for American consultative service to Indian Law Institute, 1957 (Reel P-1009)
- C-348: Association of American Colleges - Support for Commission on Colleges and Industry, 1957 (Reel P-1009)
- C-350: Support for Urban League of Westchester County, Inc. programs, 1957-1958 (Reel P-1009)
- C-351: Russell Sage College - Support for proposal to reduce teaching time, 1957 (Reel P-1009)
- C-355: Public Administration Service - Support for training program for public management, 1957 (Reel P-1009)
- C-362: Yale University - Support for astronomy program, 1957 (Reel P-1009)
- C-366: Citizens Research Council of Michigan - Support for study of public education costs in Michigan, 1957 (Reel P-1009)
- C-368: The Middle East Institute - Support for publication "Lands East", 1957 (Reel P-1009)
- C-369: American Foundation for the Aging - Support for study of the aging, 1957 (Reel P-1009)
- C-371: California Institute of Technology - Support for conference of science supervisors, 1957 (Reel P-1009)
- C-379: Fellowship program in business administration and economics, 1957-1959 (Reel P-1009, Reel P-1010)
- C-385: University of Saskatchewan - Assistance in Slavic studies, 1957-1958 (Reel P-1010)
- C-387: Cleveland International Youth Leaders Exchange Program - International Education Exchange Program, 1957 (Reel P-1010)
- C-388: International University Contact for Management Education, The Netherlands - Support for promotion and improvement of management education in Europe, 1957-1958 (Reel P-1010)
- C-392: Museum of Science and Industry, Chicago, Illinois - Support for basic investigation into educational techniques, 1957-1958 (Reel P-1010)
- C-393: Mid-west Inter-Library Center, Chicago, Illinois - Support for microfilming archives & records of Church Missionary Society, London, 1957-1959 (Reel P-1010)
- C-397: New York University - Support analysis of soviet industrial reorganization of 1957, 1957-1958 (Reel P-1010)
- C-398: Columbia University, Council for Atomic Age Studies - Survey of thought & research on problems raised for society by atomic development, 1957 (Reel P-1010)
- C-400: Institute of International Education - English language competency of foreign students in the United States, 1957-1958 (Reel P-1010)
- C-401: General support for the Oregon Shakespeare Festival Association, 1957-1958 (Reel P-1010)
- C-402: Consultant to Indonesian Council for the Sciences, 1957 (Reel P-1010)
- C-404: Community Studies, Inc. - Program for youth and child welfare in the Kansas City and Peoria Metropolitan Area, 1957 (Reel P-1010)
- C-409: The People-to-People Program - Support for program, & activities of Fine Arts Committee, 1957 (Reel P-1010)
- C-410: American Bar Foundation - Study of methods for improving conveyancing procedure and promoting marketability of land titles, 1957 (Reel P-1010)
- C-412: University of California Los Angeles - Intergroup relationships in central urban affairs & their impact on land use & housing problems, 1957 (Reel P-1010)
- C-415: International Rescue Committee, Inc. - Support for English language center, 1957 (Reel P-1010)
- C-417: Bard College - Support for the quarterly review of literature, 1957 (Reel P-1010)
- C-418: American Political Science Association - Ten year program of support, 1957-1959 (Reel P-1010)
- C-419: American Society for Public Administration - Support for activities in public administration, 1957-1958 (Reel P-1010)
- C-422: Southern Association of Nieman Fellows, Inc. - Support for fellowships for travel abroad to southern editors, 1957-1958 (Reel P-1010)
- C-424: American Association for the Advancement of Science - Support program of public education in science, 1957-1958 (Reel P-1010)
- C-425: University of Colorado - Support for School of Law, 1957-1958 (Reel P-1010)
- C-426: Massachusetts Institute of Technology (MIT) - Support for statistical investigation of labor force participation and mobility, 1957-1958 (Reel P-1010)
- C-427: Vanderbilt University - Program in business education, 1957 (Reel P-1010)
- C-429: The Association for Applied Solar Energy - Support for cooperative research program, 1957-1958 (Reel P-1010)
- C-431: European Productivity Agency - Human sciences and their application in industry, 1957-1960 (Reel P-1010)
- C-432: International Science Foundation - Support for Science Center program, 1957 (Reel P-1010)
- C-433: Inter-University Committee on International Studies - Support program of teaching & research in international field, 1957 (Reel P-1010)
- C-434: Ford Foundation - Economic Development and Administration - Summer research seminars in economics, 1957 (Reel P-1010)
- C-435: Ford Foundation - Economic Development and Administration - Summer seminars in new developments in business administration, 1957 (Reel P-1010)
- C-436: Public Management Research Institute - Validity of current assumptions concerning metropolitan government, 1957 (Reel P-1010)
- C-437: Thayer Academy - Support for Industry-Education Summer Science Advanced Study project, 1957 (Reel P-1010)
- C-438: Wayne State University - Support for journal "Background on World Politics", 1957-1958 (Reel P-1010)
- C-439: Support of activities of University Circle Development Foundation, 1957-1960 (Reel P-1010)
- C-441: College of Europe - Support for Institute for the Atlantic Community, 1957-1958 (Reel P-1011)
- C-442: University of Kansas - Evaluation of the White Physics films in secondary science education, 1957 (Reel P-1011)
- C-443: Institute of Public Affairs, University of Texas - Study of legislative interim committees in five southwestern states, 1957 (Reel P-1011)
- C-444: American Council to Improve our Neighborhoods - Investigation of urban redevelopment & renewal work, 1957 (Reel P-1011)
- C-446: RAND Corporation - Support for research on soviet economy, 1957-1958 (Reel P-1011)
- C-447: American Council to Improve our Neighborhoods - Investigation of urban redevelopment & renewal work, 1957 (Reel P-1011)
- C-449: Support for series of concerts, "Music for Moderns" - George Avakian, 1957 (Reel P-1011)
- C-451: The American Jewish Committee - Support for study of recent Jewish emigrants from the Soviet Union, 1957-1958 (Reel P-1011)
- C-452: Kansas City Art Institute and School of Design - Support studies and evaluations in field of art, 1957 (Reel P-1011)
- C-453: Lafayette College - Support for residential seminars on world affairs, 1957 (Reel P-1011)
- C-457: New York University - Institute of Fine Arts - Support for corpus of Florentine painting, 1957 (Reel P-1011)
- C-459: University of Minnesota - Support for Minnesota Music Festival, 1957 (Reel P-1011)
- C-462: Washington University, St. Louis - Support for plan for developing well trained college and university teachers, 1957-1958 (Reel P-1011)
- C-466: Georgetown University - Support for teaching of African languages and research in field of linguistics, 1957-1958 (Reel P-1011)
- C-469: University of Florida - Support for international exchange of cultural programs, 1957 (Reel P-1011)
- C-470: University of Oxford, Institute of Statistics - Surveys of income and savings, 1958-1959, 1957 (Reel P-1011)
- C-471: Center for Research on Business, 1957-1959 (Reel P-1011)
- C-473: Colgate University - Support for program in economic development and business administration, 1957-1958 (Reel P-1011)
- C-476: National Municipal League - Support project to promote practical democracy in big cities, 1958-1959 (Reel P-1011)
- C-478: University of Cinncinnati - Support for Institute of Comparative Law and Comparative Government, 1958 (Reel P-1011)
- C-480: Association for Asian Studies, Inc. - Support for summer programs on Asia, 1957-1958 (Reel P-1011)
- C-481: Stanford University - Support for study center, Stuttgart, Germany, 1958 (Reel P-1011)
- C-482: Occidental College - Support for program in diplomacy and world affairs, 1958 (Reel P-1011)
- C-484: University of Cornell and University of Chicago - Support for study of federal executives, 1958 (Reel P-1011)
- C-487: University of California (Berkeley) Support for three institutes for junior college teachers of engineering, 1958 (Reel P-1011)
- C-488: Social Sciences and Business Administration (Ford Foundation initiated), 1958 (Reel P-1011)
- C-493: Federal Government Accountants Association - Support for program to improve financial administration in federal government, 1958 (Reel P-1011)
- C-494: Humanities Research Council of Canada - Support for general program, 1958 (Reel P-1011)
- C-495: Human Relations Area Files (Yale University) - Support for an Asian encyclopedia, 1958 (Reel P-1011)
- C-496: Office of Education (Department of Health, Education and Welfare) - Completion of nationwide inventory of higher education facilities, 1958 (Reel P-1011)
- C-500: National Conference of Christians and Jews - Intergroup skills and community leadership through an experiment in intercultural travel, 1958 (Reel P-1011)
- C-501: Support program of making Japanese sociological material available in abstracts form, 1958 (Reel P-1011)
- C-504: Princeton University - Support for Princeton archeological expedition to Sicily, Italy, 1958 (Reel P-1011)
- C-505: University of Michigan - Support follow-up of the Tee Study reported in personality and social change, 1958 (Reel P-1011)
- C-507: International Commission of Jurists, The Hague, Netherlands - Support for congress of jusrists in Asia, January 1959, 1958-1959 (Reel P-1012)
- C-510: International Alliance of Women, Denmark - Mutual appreciation of Eastern and Western cultural values, 1958 (Reel P-1012)
- C-512: University of Kansas - Support proposal to utilize an analogue computer to investigate instability properties of international economic systems, 1958 (Reel P-1012)
- C-513: International Association for the Exchange of Students for Technical Experience - General support, 1958 (Reel P-1012)
- C-515: Franklin and Marshall College - College interest program, 1958 (Reel P-1012)
- C-517: Dorr Foundation - Support for pre-college science center, 1958 (Reel P-1012)
- C-518: Brown University, Rhode Island School of Design - Support for center for regional studies and planning, 1958 (Reel P-1012)
- C-520: Association of American Universities - Neighborhood problems of urban universities, 1958 (Reel P-1012)
- C-523: University of Michigan - Support for research program in application of subliminal perception, 1958 (Reel P-1012)
- C-524: National Institute for Architectural Education - International exhibition of work of students of architecture, 1958 (Reel P-1012)
- C-525: North Central Association of Colleges and Secondary Schools, 1958 (Reel P-1012)
- C-526: Meadowlands Regional Planning Board - Support for reclamation and development of Hackensack meadows [New Jersey], 1958 (Reel P-1012)
- C-527: Cornell University - Support for survey of engineering profession, 1958 (Reel P-1012)
- C-531: Morgan State College - Science manpower project, 1958 (Reel P-1012)
- C-535: Cornell University - Support for studies of constitutional law decisions, 1958 (Reel P-1012)
- C-537: Phoenix Theatre, New York - Support to establish a permanent repertory company, 1958 (Reel P-1012)
- C-539: Ministry of Economic Affairs, Government of Pakistan - Architectural supervision of Ford Foundation-assisted projects, 1958 (Reel P-1012)
- C-548: Columbia University - Research in patterns of succession in organizations, 1958 (Reel P-1012)
- C-549: Drexel Institute of Technology - Training of teachers of science and mathematics, 1958 (Reel P-1012)
- C-552: Washington University, St. Louis - Training of retired executives and professional persons for college teaching, 1958 (Reel P-1012)
- C-553: Johns Hopkins University - Center for quantitative study of comparative economic structure and growth, 1957-1959 (Reel P-1012)
- C-554: New York University, School of Law - Establishement of judicial internships, 1958 (Reel P-1012)
- C-555: University of Michigan Law School - Supplementing the adversary process in family litigation, 1958 (Reel P-1012)
- C-556: University of Kansas - Research on "MTS: Its demise and transformation of the Kolkhozy into Sovkhozy" [Soviet collective farm system], 1958 (Reel P-1012)
- C-557: University of Santa Clara - Survey of social science in modern management, 1958 (Reel P-1012)
- C-559: University of Pennsylvania - Research in economics basic to public and business policy, 1958-1963 (Reel P-1012)
- C-560: Stanford University - Interdisciplinary study and teaching program in antitrust policy, 1958 (Reel P-1012)
- C-564: Lehigh University - Theory of consumer behavior for differentiated products, 1958 (Reel P-1012)
- C-566: Faculty and student research related to public affairs (Ford Foundation initiated), 1957-1958 (Reel P-1012)
- C-567: Michigan State University - Support of integration of behavioral science into cirriculum, 1958 (Reel P-1012)
- C-572: Program in aging (Ford Foundation initiated), 1957-1962 (Reel P-1012)
- C-574: Georgia Institute of Technology - Training program for professional personnel of state and territorial regulatory commissions, 1958 (Reel P-1012)
- C-575: American Political Science Association - Experimental courses in Political Science at introductory level, 1957 (Reel P-1012)
- C-577: University of Washington, Seattle - Financial aid to doctoral candidates in business administration, 1958 (Reel P-1012)
- C-581: University of Santa Clara (California) - Study of development of need for business administrators in Guadalajara region of Mexico, 1958 (Reel P-1012)
- C-583: Middle East Institute - Support for general program, 1958 (Reel P-1012)
- C-585: Utah State University - Middle East educational program, 1958 (Reel P-1012)
- C-586: Rhodes-Livingston Museum, Livingstone, Rhodesia - Support for general program, 1958 (Reel P-1012)
- C-587: Liberian-United States Joint Commission for Economic Development - Establishment of a rural elementary teacher training institution, 1958 (Reel P-1012)
- C-590: International Institute of Differing Civilizations (Brussels, Belgium), 1958 (Reel P-1012)
- C-591: International Committee for Social Sciences Documentation - Support for general program, 1958 (Reel P-1012)
- C-593: Preparation of courses [in Biology, Chemistry, Great Issues, Mathematics, and Psychology] on film (Ford Foundation initiated), 1958 (Reel P-1012)
- C-595: Scientific activities in Atlantic community (Ford Foundation initiated), 1957 (Reel P-1012)
- C-598: Senior Living, Inc. - New living arrangements in Boston for older men and women of moderate means, 1958 (Reel P-1012)
- C-599: University of Bridgeport - Study of interrelationships between art and industrial design, 1958 (Reel P-1012)
- C-600: University of Bridgeport - Experimental community art center, 1958 (Reel P-1012)
- C-606: The Child Study Center, Institute of the Pennsylvania Hospital - Relationship of nursery school attendance to health, social, and emotional development, 1958 (Reel P-1012)
- C-609: University of Hawaii - Research project in field of science teaching, 1958 (Reel P-1012)
- C-610: Case studies of metropolitan action programs (Ford Foundation initiated), 1958 (Reel P-1012)
- C-616: Aleppo College - General Program, 1955-1958 (Reel P-1012)
- C-618: Indiana University - Experimental graduate programs, 1958 (Reel P-1012)
- C-620: Grants In Aid program for visual artists (Ford Foundation initiated), 1958-1959 (Reel P-1012, Reel P-1013)
  See also Ford Foundation Grant files: 05900120 (PA59-120), Foundation-Administered Project (FAP), PROGRAM FOR VISUAL ARTISTS; 06000084 (PA60-84), Foundation-Administered Project (FAP), PROGRAM FOR VISUAL ARTISTS; and 06090071 (PA60-71), Foundation-Administered Project (FAP), PURCHASE PRIZES AWARDED IN CONNECTION WITH 1959 PROGRAM FOR VISUAL ARTISTS.
  Grantees include: Josef Albers, Elmer Bishoff, Hyman Bloom, Edwin Dickinson, Philip Guston, Raoul Hague, Conrad Marca-Relli, Reuben Nakian, Theodore Roszak, Adja Yunkers.
  Includes correspondence with Lucy R. Lippard.
- C-621: Grants In Aid program for performers in music (Ford Foundation initiated), 1958-1959 (Reel P-1013)
  See also: Ford Foundation records, Grants, 05900152 (PA59-152), "PERFORMING MUSICAL ARTISTS".
  Grantees include: Adele Addison, Phyllis Curtin, Leon Fleischer, Joseph Fuchs, Irene Jordan, Jaboc Lateiner, Symour Lipkin, William Masselos, Michael Rabin, Leonard Rose.
- C-622: Grants in Aid program for directors in theater (Ford Foundation initiated), 1958-1959 (Reel P-1013)
  See also: Ford Foundation records, Grants, 05900115 (PA59-115), Foundation-Administered Project (FAP), "PROGRAM FOR DIRECTORS".
  See also: Ford Foundation records, Grants, 06000136 (PA60-136), Foundation-Administered Project (FAP), "PROGRAM FOR DIRECTORS IN THE PROFESSIONAL THEATER".
  Grantees include: William Ball, New York, Director of Ivanov, etc.; Rachmael ben Avram, Director, Company of the Golden Hind, Berkeley, California; Angus L. Blau, Director, Actor's Workshop, San Francisco; James H. Clancy, Director in the theater of the State University of Iowa; Zelda Fichandler, Producing Director, Arena Stage, Washington, D.C.; John Reich, Head, Goodman Memorial Theatre, Chicago; Alan Schneider, New York Director of the Remarkable Mr. Pennypacker, Endgame, Anastasia, etc.; Mack Scism, Director, Mummers Theatre, Oklahoma City; Nina Vance, Managing Director, Alley Theatre, Houston.
- C-623: Grants in Aid program for the playwright in theater (Ford Foundation initiated), 1958-1959 (Reel P-1013, Reel P-1014)
  See also: Ford Foundation records, Grants, 05800294 (PA58-294), "GRANTS-IN-AID PROGRAM FOR PLAYWRIGHTS".
  Grantees include: James Adams, Swamp Song; Edwin Harvey Blum, The Saving Grace; Kenneth Cameron, The Physician for Fools; Thomas P. Cullinan, Madigan's Wedding; Josh Greenfield, Clandestine on the Morning Line; John B. Harding, Kinderspiel; Sidney Michaels, The Plaster Bambino; Phillip Pruneau, the Morgan Rock; Seyril Schochen, The Moon Besieged; Miriam Stoval, Reap the Whirlwind; John Vlahos, The Golden Age of Pericles Pappas; R.G. Vilet, The Regions of Noon; Lionel Wiggam, Inside Emily Payne.
- C-624: Visiting professorships for social scientists at business schools (Ford Foundation initiated), 1958-1959 (Reel P-1014)
- C-625: Faculty study fellowships in the social sciences (Ford Foundation initiated), 1958 (Reel P-1014)
- C-627: International Council of Philosophy and Humanistic Studies - Meeting of the fifth general assembly in 1959, 1958 (Reel P-1014)
- C-628: New York University, College of Engineering - Solar cooking oven, preparation of models for experimental demonstration purposes, 1958-1962 (Reel P-1014)
- C-629: Master fellowships for graduate school (Ford Foundation initiated), 1958 (Reel P-1014)
- C-630: Massachesetts Institute of Technology (MIT) - Study of urban design achievments of past civilizations and cultures, 1958 (Reel P-1014)
- C-631: Detroit Municipal Opera Inc. - Opera workshops for Detroit, Michigan, 1958 (Reel P-1014)
- C-633: Montana State College - Graduate study program in international technical cooperation, 1958-1963 (Reel P-1014)
- C-634: American University at Cairo - Training and research program, 1958-1960 (Reel P-1014)
- C-636: University of Notre Dame - Exchange of faculty and graduate students with universities in Poland, 1958-1960 (Reel P-1014)
- C-638: Program for the creative writer (Ford Foundation initiated), 1958-1959 (Reel P-1015)
  See also: Ford Foundation records, Projects, C-918: Grants in Aid program for novelists and poets.
  See also: Ford Foundation records, Grants, 05900121 (PA59-121), "PROGRAM FOR CREATIVE WRITERS".
  See also: Ford Foundation records, Grants, 06000132 (PA60-132), Foundation-Administered Project (FAP), "PROGRAM FOR POETS AND FICTION WRITERS".
  Grantees include: James Baldwin, Saul Bellow, E.E. Cummings, Robert Fitzgerald, Stanley J. Kunitz, Bernard Malmud, Flannery O'Connor, Tillie Olsen, Katherine Anne Porter, Theodore H. Roethke, and Niccolo Tucci.
- C-640: Governmental Affairs Institute - Assistance in emergency cases to visiting Russian delegations, 1958 (Reel P-1014)
- C-642: Study of philanthropy (Ford Foundation initiated), 1954-1956 (Reel P-1014)
- C-644: Minnesota, State of - Project for mobilizing community services, 1958 (Reel P-1014)
- C-647: Graduate reearch seminars in economics: Ford Foundation - Economic Development and Administration (EDA) (Reel P-1014)
- C-650: Exploratory conferences and projects on economics of education (Ford Foundation initiated), 1958-1959 (Reel P-1015)
- C-651: American Public Health Association - Study of methods of improving local services for the aged, 1958 (Reel P-1015)
- C-652: Ontario Society on Aging (Canada) - Assistance for Ontario Society on Aging, 1958 (Reel P-1015)
- C-654: Cornell College - Public Affairs and civic responsibilities, 1958 (Reel P-1015)
- C-656: Iraq (Ministry of Finance) - Advisors for public administration, 1958 (Reel P-1015)
- C-658: Barter Theatre of Virginia, Inc. - Support to initiate and develop a year round repertory company, 1958 (Reel P-1015)
- C-659: Hispanic Council, Luso-Brazilian Council - Interchange of visits between Brazil and Great Britain, 1958 (Reel P-1015)
- C-660: Municipal Finance Officers Association - Examination of the role of local finance in our national life, 1958 (Reel P-1015)
- C-662: San Francisco Senior Center - Training personnel for services and programs for older people, 1958-1959 (Reel P-1015)
- C-664: Carrie Chapman Catt Memorial Fund, Inc. - International exchange for education in public affairs, 1958 (Reel P-1015)
- C-665: American Association for the Advancement of Science - International oceanographic congress, 1958 (Reel P-1015)
- C-666: Association for Asian Studies - Cooperative development of American far eastern library resources, 1958 (Reel P-1015)
- C-668: University of Chicago - Program of Japanese studies, 1958 (Reel P-1015)
- C-671: National Association of County Officials - Comparative county government project, 1958 (Reel P-1015)
- C-673: Citizens' Housing and Planning Council of New York, Inc. - Housing and urban renewal program for the United States, 1957-1958 (Reel P-1015)